## Andrew Mason

#### **Profile**

Full stack Ruby on Rails software engineer with 3.5 years of professional experience at small and medium sized companies. I work best in fast-paced, agile environments where I can have high impact and work on all ends of the stack. My passion for creating has led to many open source contributions to libraries like StimulusReflex, CableReady, Bridgetown, and more. In my spare time, I co-host podcasts and write a newsletter for the Ruby community.

## **Professional Experience**

#### The N2 Company, Software Developer

11/2020 - present

Remote

- Orchestrated the design and development of a new, internal Ruby on Rails sales application through close collaboration with stakeholders and project managers
- Mentored and onboarded new developers onto the team and conducted code reviews across several Ruby on Rails applications and microservices
- Resolved support tickets through code investigation and cross-team communication in a fast-paced environment to enhance the experience of users and increase customer satisfaction
- Enhanced and expanded a movement from using a custom Docker and Terraform DevOps architecture to Heroku

### Realvolve, Inc., Software Engineer

CodeFund, Software Engineer

08/2020 - 11/2020

- Maintained and enhanced features in a large, legacy Ruby on Rails 4 application
- Collaborated with vendors to create a robust integration into an AI chatbot.
- Enhanced internal tooling with a focus on cleaning up tech debt and improving the test suite and testing practices.

- Lead development on a Ruby on Rails monolith, with heavy usage of StimulusReflex and CableReady, using agile methodologies
- Started an initiative to redo the entire frontend in Tailwind CSS and ViewComponent
- Created continuous integration workflows to maintain the integrity of the system and automate parts of the code review process
- Managed and owned feature development from design to implementation and maintained the integrity of the application through refactoring and bug resolution
- Facilitated deployments and implemented enhancements to the DevOps workflow

# **N2 Publishing,** Software Developer

 Collaborated closely with designers and product managers to build high-quality, internal software applications to automate processes and enhance workflows

- Architected and developed complex workflows for processing PDF documents at different steps in the design and production process
- Developed tested features for a new production and shipping management system, that utilized Ruby on Rails, which tracked publications' production status, transferred the publications to commercial printing equipment, and managed shipping information
- Tracked and solved support desk tickets spanning multiple Ruby on Rails applications

## 05/2018 - 10/2019 Wilmington, NC

#### **Education**

University of North Carolina at Wilmington, Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

- Graduated Cum Laude with a 3.7 GPA, and was on the Deans list from 2014-2017
- Became a member of Upsilon Pi Epsilon: International Honor Society for the Computing and Information Disciplines: 2017

08/2014 - 05/2018 Wilmington, NC

Remote

10/2019 - 06/2020

Remote